Register of the Russell McCulloch Story Papers, 1917-1921
Hoover Institution Archives
Russell McCulloch Story Papers,
1917-1921
57009
Story, Russell McCulloch, 1883-1942
1 manuscript box, 6 glass slide boxes, 1 envelope 1.8 linear feet)
Hoover Institution Archives Stanford, California 94305-6010
Letters, photographs, and glass slides, relating to relief work in Russia, conditions in Moscow and elsewhere in Russia during the Russian Revolution, and the Czechoslovak Legion; and depicting scenes in Japan, Russia and western Europe
Administrative Information
Access
Collection open for research.
The Hoover Institution Archives only allows access to copies of audiovisual items. To listen to sound recordings or to view videos or films during your visit, please contact the Archives at least two working days before your arrival. We will then advise you of the accessibility of the material you wish to see or hear. Please note that not all audiovisual material is immediately accessible.
Acquisition Information
Acquired by the Hoover Institution Archives in 1957.
Accruals
Materials may have been added to the collection since this finding aid was prepared. To determine if this has occurred, find the collection in Stanford University's online catalog Socrates at http://library.stanford.edu/webcat. Materials have been added to the collection if the number of boxes listed in Socrates is larger than the number of boxes listed in this finding aid.
Access Points
Russia. Armiia. Ceskoslovensky strelecky pluk; Young Men's Christian Associations; International relief; Czechoslovakia; Soviet Union; Russia (Federation); Soviet Union--History--Revolution, 1917-1921--Civilian relief; Soviet Union--History--Allied intervention, 1918-1920; Slides (Photography)
Biographical Note
Story, Russell McCulloch, 1883-1942
1883, April 9 Born, Washburn, Illinois
1904 A.B. Monmouth (Ill.) College
1908 A.M., Harvard
1909 Married Gertrude Anderson of Pawnee City, Neb.
1909-10 Teacher at Clark College
1910-14 Professor of History at Monmouth College
1914-24 Instructor, Asst. and Assoc. Professor, and Professor of Political Science, Univ. of Illinois.
1917 Ph.D., Harvard
1917 author, THE AMERICAN MUNICIPAL EXECUTIVE
1917-18 War Work Secretary for Y.M.C.A. in Russia and Siberia
1919 decorated Cross of War (Czechoslovakia)
1924-25 Professor of Political Science, Syracuse U.
1925-37 Professor of Political Science, Pomona College
1937-42 President of Claremont Colleges
Container List
- Glass slides of photographs taken in Russia and Japan, 1917-1919 (Box 1-5.)
- Letters from Russell M. Story to Gertrude Story and others, 1917-1918 (Box 6.)
  - Unnumbered, October 1917, en route to Hawaii
  - No. 1, October 7-10, 1917, en route to Japan
  - No. 2, October 21, 1917, Yokohama
  - Unnumbered, October 22, 1917, Yokohama
  - Unnumbered, October 23, 1917, Tsuruga
  - No. 4, October 27, 1917, on board Trans-Siberian Express
  - No. 6, November 2, 1917 (Russian date, October 22), Vologda
  - No. 7, November 8, 1917, Moscow
  - No. 8, November 9, 1917, Moscow
  - No. 9, November 15, 1917, Moscow
  - No. 10, November 20, 1917, Moscow
  - No. 11, November 24, Moscow
  - No. 12, November 27, 1917, Moscow
  - No. 13, December 4, 1917, Moscow
  - No. 14, December 9, 1917, Moscow
  - No. 15, December 11, 1917, Moscow
  - No. 16, December 16, 1917, Moscow
  - No. 17, December 23, 1917, Moscow
  - No. 18, December 28, 1917, Moscow
  - No. 19, December 30, 1917, Moscow
  - No. 21, January 18, 1918, Petrograd
  - Unnumbered, January 19, 1918, Haparanda, Sweden
  - Unnumbered, January 29, 1918, Stockholm, Sweden
  - No. 22, January 29, 1918, Stockholm
  - No. 24, February 13, 1918, Stockholm
  - Unnumbered, February 17, 1918, Stockholm
  - No. 25, February 25, 1918, Tornio, Finland
  - Unnumbered, February 26, 1918, probably Tornio, Finland
  - Unnumbered, March 4, 1918, Sortavala, Finland
  - Unnumbered, March 8, 1918, Suojärvi, Finland
  - No. 27, March 15, 1918, Moscow
  - No. 28, March 17, 1918, en route to Samara from Moscow
  - No. 29, March 22, 1918, Samara
  - No. 30, April 20, 1918 and April 27, 1918, en route to Vladivostock and in Vladivostock
  - No. 31, May 1, 1918, Vladivostock
  - Unnumbered, May 9, 1918, Harbin, Manchuria
  - Unnumbered, May 12, 1918, Harbin, Manchuria (to his parents)
  - Unnumbered, May 14, 1918, Harbin, Manchuria
  - Unnumbered, May 18, 1918, Harbin, Manchuria (to Colton)
  - Unnumbered, May 22, 1918, Vladivostock
  - Unnumbered, June 1, 1918, Vladivostock
  - Unnumbered, June 8, 1918 and June 13, 1918, on board the Simbirsk en route to Yokohama from Vladivostok
  - Unnumbered, June 13, 1918, Yokohama
  - Unnumbered, June 15, 1918, on board S.S. Hozan Maru, en route to Vladivostok (to U.S. Ambassador, Tokyo)
  - Unnumbered, June 23, 1918, Vladivostok
  - Unnumbered, July 10, 1918, Vladivostok
  - Unnumbered, July 14, 1918, Vladivostok (to his family)
  - Unnumbered, July 14, 1918, Vladivostok
  - Unnumbered, July 27, 1918, Vladivostok
  - Unnumbered, July 31, 1918, Vladivostok
  - Unnumbered, August 7, 1918, Vladivostok
  - Unnumbered, August 12, 1918, Vladivostok (?)
  - Unnumbered, August 24, 1918, Vladivostok
  - Unnumbered, August 28, 1918, Vladivostok
  - Unnumbered, September 1, 1918, Vladivostok (to his family)
  - Unnumbered, September 1, 1918, Vladivostok
  - Unnumbered, September 17, 1918, Vladivostok
  - Unnumbered, October 7, 1918, Vladivostok
  - Unnumbered, November 8, 1917, Vladivostok
  - Unnumbered, December 14, 1918, Seattle, Washington
- Miscellaneous letters received, 1917-1921
- Reports and pamphlets on the work of the Y.M.C.A. in Russia and Czechoslovakia between 1917 and 1919
- Czechoslovakia Cross of War, certificate and correspondence
- Passports
- Glass slides of photographs taken in Russia and Japan, 1917-1919 (Box 7.)